<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ressources on Hacking My Life</title>
    <link>https://P0ulp1.github.io/tags/ressources/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ressources on Hacking My Life</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 11:43:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://P0ulp1.github.io/tags/ressources/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Complete Beginner Guide to CyberSec and Pentesting</title>
      <link>https://P0ulp1.github.io/posts/complete-beginner-guide-to-cybersec-and-pentesting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Jul 2022 11:43:36 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://P0ulp1.github.io/posts/complete-beginner-guide-to-cybersec-and-pentesting/</guid>
      <description>Hello there ! This is my first post on this blog, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to give some advices I learned while trying to learn CyberSecurity and Pentesting more specifically. This page is subject to a lot of changes. By writing these lines, I&amp;rsquo;m still a beginner but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I can&amp;rsquo;t try to help you ! I&amp;rsquo;ve scattered the web a lot, searching for the best ressources out there to learn these skills that you may want to learn too if you&amp;rsquo;re here, reading a lot of reviews, asking questions to relevant persons, IRL and on the Internet.</description>
      <content>&lt;h1 id=&#34;hello-there-&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Hello there !&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is my first post on this blog, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to give some advices I learned while trying to learn CyberSecurity and Pentesting more specifically. This page is subject to &lt;strong&gt;a lot&lt;/strong&gt; of changes. By writing these lines, I&amp;rsquo;m still a &lt;strong&gt;beginner&lt;/strong&gt; but that doesn&amp;rsquo;t mean I can&amp;rsquo;t try to help you ! &lt;strong&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve scattered the web a lot&lt;/strong&gt;, searching for the best ressources out there to learn these skills that you may want to learn too if you&amp;rsquo;re here, reading a lot of reviews, asking questions to relevant persons, IRL and on the Internet. I&amp;rsquo;ll try to always give you &lt;strong&gt;links&lt;/strong&gt; to discussions thread that speak about the mentionned ressource, so people that know better than myself (and there&amp;rsquo;s a lot) can help you too. I will try to put a section with general advices that can help to &lt;strong&gt;learn a lot of things by yourself&lt;/strong&gt;, like CyberSec but in general everything related to &lt;strong&gt;self-taught&lt;/strong&gt;. If you have questions or comment that can be useful, you can &lt;a href=&#34;https://P0ulp1.github.io/about&#34;&gt;PM me&lt;/a&gt; on differents socials, I&amp;rsquo;d be happy to talk with you :)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Note : I will use the word &amp;ldquo;pentesting&amp;rdquo; for everything related to CyberSec skills, it&amp;rsquo;s juste more convenient, but a lot of those ressources can be useful for a big range of &lt;strong&gt;Computer Skills&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;summary&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Summary&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Explanation of Chapters&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;
&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[0.0] Foreword&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;[0.1] Pre-Pre Requisites&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;explanation-of-chapters&#34;&gt;Explanation of Chapters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;0 -&amp;gt; The start of the start. Ressources and advices for people who barely know what a &lt;strong&gt;VM&lt;/strong&gt; is, who don&amp;rsquo;t know how to use &lt;strong&gt;Linux&lt;/strong&gt;, don&amp;rsquo;t have &lt;strong&gt;Basic Networking Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; and these kind of stuff. If you don&amp;rsquo;t understand a heck about what I&amp;rsquo;m talking about, then you should &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; start here.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;00-foreword&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[0.0] Foreword&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Pentesting, CyberSec, Hacking, call it what you want, is &lt;strong&gt;Hard&lt;/strong&gt;. I don&amp;rsquo;t want to discourage you, but let&amp;rsquo;s be honnest, it is. You would&amp;rsquo;nt call yourself a writer because you wrote 2 essays at school that gave you a great mark or if you just red a lot of books. To become a writer, you have to write. Well to become a Pentester, &lt;strong&gt;you have to pentest&lt;/strong&gt;. If possible &lt;strong&gt;everyday&lt;/strong&gt; depending of your schedule. You have to do as much hands-on as you can, when you learn something, see something new, &lt;strong&gt;try it&lt;/strong&gt; immediatly, the information is fresh in your brain, and you don&amp;rsquo;t want it to go, so do it &lt;strong&gt;again and again and again and again&lt;/strong&gt;, that&amp;rsquo;s one of the best advice for everything self-taught. Don&amp;rsquo;t get me wrong, it&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;really&lt;/strong&gt; important to read man pages, take courses (just don&amp;rsquo;t take so many that you will end up not going deep enough for each subject) but &lt;strong&gt;hands-on&lt;/strong&gt; is what will make the &lt;strong&gt;knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; stick in your head for &lt;strong&gt;ever&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id=&#34;01-pre-requisites&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;[0.1] Pre Requisites&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here, I will list &lt;strong&gt;ressources&lt;/strong&gt; that can help you build that strong &lt;strong&gt;Basic Knowledge&lt;/strong&gt; about computers in general that you&amp;rsquo;re &lt;strong&gt;definitely&lt;/strong&gt; gonna need. Pentesting is kind of requiring you to know a lot of skills related to &lt;strong&gt;Computer Science&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you start from here, I just want to say that it&amp;rsquo;s going to be a &lt;strong&gt;looooong&lt;/strong&gt; journey, so buckle up, get motivated, and don&amp;rsquo;t stop until you &lt;strong&gt;achieved your goal&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;First of all is English, you&amp;rsquo;re gonna need it. If it&amp;rsquo;s not your foreign language, learn it as much as you can, it must become your new language, think in English, do everything computer-related in English, watch movies/shows/news in English, read books, use translators whenever you find a word you didn&amp;rsquo;t know about before, everything will help you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;[MORE SOON]&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
